# GERLIS ALVAREZ CARDONA

Web developer

Cartagena, Colombia gerlis1997@gmail.com +573008511771

#### **DETAILS**

**Nationality** 

Colombian

#### **PROFILE**

I'm a software developer with 5 years of experience building web-based solutions. I have been working in front-end development with JavaScript and TypeScript technologies, mainly with Angular and React. I have experience working for small and medium-sized companies building complex front-end projects, knowledgeable in user interface, testing, and debugging processes.

I like to stay updated with cutting-edge advancements, collaborate well with development teams and UX/UI designers, work alongside senior developers, and mentor less experienced team members.

#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### Web developer, Intergrupo, Sabaneta

OCTOBER 2017 - SEPTEMBER 2021

- Refactored react components from class to functional components minimizing their complexity and becoming more maintainable and scalable components.
- Implemented components within a storybook library generating access to the components and their functionality before its actual implementation.
- Augmented code comprehension by building components with a higher code reuse rate and increased robustness with unit testing.
- Participated in code reviews and mentored junior developers

#### Frontend Developer, Lean Tech, Medellín

OCTOBER 2021 - PRESENT

- Maintaining and improving different apps based on Angular and React using web standards with BEM for CSS
- Development of React web functional components in microfrontend-based architecture projects.
- Refactored various components built in TypeScript with Bootstrap styles library and with Redux as global information source.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Análisis y Desarrollo de Sistemas de Información, Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje (SENA)

JULY 2015 - NOVEMBER 2017

Graduated from the Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje (SENA) under the title of Technologist in Analysis and Information Development.

LINKS

## Personal Twiiter LinkedIn

# SKILLS

Javascript Typescript

React Angular

HTML5 CSS3

Node.js Material UI

Bootstrap GIT

Continuous Integration (Azure)

### LANGUAGES

English

## REFERENCES

References available upon request

# HOBBIES

Listen to Music, Playing guitar, playing video games.